<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3541">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on September 19, 2022</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01905436</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>201107185</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01905436</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mass Drug Administration for Lymphatic Filariasis and Onchocerciasis for Liberia</brief_title>
  <acronym>DOLF-LIBERIA</acronym>
  <official_title>Optimization of Mass Drug Administration With Existing Drug Regimens for Lymphatic Filariasis and Onchocerciasis for Liberia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Washington University School of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Washington University School of Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Approximately 5,200 people will participate per year. The study population will include&#xD;
      females and males over 5 years of age who live in filariasis and onchocerciasis endemic&#xD;
      areas. Subject selection will not be based on health status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two sites will be studied, and each study will last for 4 years. Participants will be studied&#xD;
      only once in cross-sectional surveys. Some subjects may be included in more than one annual&#xD;
      population survey, but this is not a longitudinal study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investigators will compare annual and semiannual mass drug administration (MDA) for lymphatic&#xD;
      filariasis and onchocerciasis, and investigators will compare the impact of these MDA&#xD;
      schedules on soil transmitted helminth infections. MDA will be administered by others&#xD;
      (Liberian Ministry of Health or Liberian Institute of Biomedical Research).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will test the hypothesis that semiannual mass drug administration (MDA) is&#xD;
      superior to annual MDA for elimination of lymphatic filariasis, onchocerciasis and for&#xD;
      control of soil transmitted helminth (STH) infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Compare the relative impact and cost effectiveness of annual vs. twice yearly mass drug&#xD;
           administration (MDA) for elimination of lymphatic filariasis (LF) in these populations.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Compare the relative impact and cost effectiveness of annual vs. twice yearly mass drug&#xD;
           administration (MDA) for elimination of onchocerciasis in these populations.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Study the impact of annual vs. semiannual MDA on soil transmitted helminth (STH)&#xD;
           infection in these populations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Continuation Activities (2019/2020):&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additional one-time cross-sectional surveys will be completed in the Harper site in Maryland&#xD;
      district in 2019 and in Lofa in 2020 to measure the long-term impact of MDA on W. bancrofti,&#xD;
      O. volvulus, and on STH infection parameters following these cumulative 7-9 rounds of MDA&#xD;
      since the baseline survey taken in 2013. Since the last DOLF surveys (3rd follow-ups) in&#xD;
      these sites in 2016 &amp; 2017, respectively, there have been a total of 3 annual rounds of MDA&#xD;
      in both areas. These additional surveys will recruit 2,500 participants in the Maryland area&#xD;
      villages and 3,200 in the Lofa area villages.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Lymphatic filariasis (LF) is a deforming and disabling infectious disease that causes&#xD;
      elephantiasis and genital deformity (especially hydroceles). The infection affects some 120&#xD;
      million people in 81 countries in tropical and subtropical regions with well over 1 billion&#xD;
      people at risk of acquiring the disease [1]. LF is caused by Wuchereria bancrofti and Brugia&#xD;
      spp. (B. malayi and B.timori), nematode parasites that are transmitted by mosquitoes. This&#xD;
      study is based on the assumption that currently used MDA regimens and schedules are not&#xD;
      optimal for achieving elimination of LF. These regimens (either annual Albendazole (Alb) 400&#xD;
      mg plus diethylcarbamazine 6 mg/kg or Alb 400 mg plus Ivermectin (Iver) 200 µg/kg for LF)&#xD;
      were introduced more than 10 years ago.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Onchocerciasis (&quot;Oncho&quot;) is similar in some ways to LF in that it is a vector-borne nematode&#xD;
      parasitic disease that causes severe disability. In contrast to LF, this disease causes&#xD;
      blindness and severe skin disease rather than elephantiasis, and it is spread by black flies&#xD;
      instead of mosquitoes. O. volvulus adult worms live in subcutaneous nodules while the adult&#xD;
      worms of the LF parasites live in lymphatic vessels. O. volvulus adult worms are larger and&#xD;
      less sensitive to available drug treatments than those of the species that cause LF and have&#xD;
      a longer lifespan (approximately 14 years rather than the estimated 7 years for LF&#xD;
      parasites). More effective drugs or dosing schedules for MDA against Oncho could shorten the&#xD;
      number of years needed to interrupt Oncho transmission in areas that previously had high&#xD;
      disease rates.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Drugs used for LF MDA are also active against soil transmitted helminth infections (STH,&#xD;
      e.g., Ascaris, Hookworm, and Trichuris). De-worming campaigns using anthelmintics usually&#xD;
      target special groups of the population, such as schoolchildren, and have limited impact on&#xD;
      transmission. Treatment of the total population and semiannual treatments may reduce&#xD;
      re-infection considerably and will most likely lead to reduced infection densities and&#xD;
      infection prevalence rates. Suppression of STH is an important ancillary benefit of MDA&#xD;
      programs for filarial infections. Increasingly control programs for filariasis and STH are&#xD;
      being integrated with programs for other parasitic diseases such as schistosomiasis. For this&#xD;
      reason, participants will also be tested for schistosomiasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Purpose: The study aims to compare the effectiveness once yearly (1X) versus twice yearly&#xD;
      (2X) mass drug administration (MDA) for the elimination of lymphatic filariasis,&#xD;
      onchocerciasis and for control of soil-transmitted helminth infections (intestinal parasites)&#xD;
      in large populations. Mass drug administration will be provided by the Liberian Ministry of&#xD;
      Health. This project will assess the impact of the government's public health program.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures: Study procedures include collection of finger prick blood that will be tested for&#xD;
      microfilariae by microscopy and for serology testing (antigenemia and antibody testing). Skin&#xD;
      snips will be collected and examined by microscopy for the presence of Onchocerca&#xD;
      microfilariae. Stool samples will be collected for detection of parasitic worm eggs by&#xD;
      microscopy. All assays will be performed in Liberia (filarial serology tests, microfilaria&#xD;
      testing, stool examinations).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Washington University researchers developed the protocol, will provide training and guidance&#xD;
      to Liberian researchers, and work with them to analyze the data. Liberian researchers will&#xD;
      consent the participants, obtain blood, skin and stool specimens, perform laboratory tests on&#xD;
      the specimens, and enter data on participants and lab results.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Ecologic or Community</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of W. bancrofti microfilaria (4 years)</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Prevalence of W. bancrofti microfilaria (mf) is a binary outcome measured by the presence/absence of W. bancrofti mf in three-line thick smears prepared with a measured 60 microliter quantity of finger prick blood collected between 8pm-2am. The species of mf will be determined by morphological criteria.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of W. bancrofti filarial antigenemia (4 years)</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Prevalence of this outcome measure is determined by the percentage (%) of individuals with positive tests for the W. bancrofti filarial antigen. Blood will be tested for filarial antigenemia using the Alere Filariasis Test Strip (FTS).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of O. volvulus microfilaria (4 years)</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Prevalence of O. volvulus microfilaria (mf) is a binary outcome measured by the presence/absence of O. volvulus mf taken from skin snips using Holth corneoscleral punches taken from the buttocks.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Community egg load of soil transmitted helminth (STH) eggs (4 years)</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Community egg load is defined as average stool egg count per species. FLOTAC and Kato-Katz (KK) methods will be used to examine a single stool sample from each subject.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of W. bancrofti microfilaria (7 years)</measure>
    <time_frame>7 years</time_frame>
    <description>Prevalence of W. bancrofti microfilaria (mf) is a binary outcome measured by the presence/absence of W. bancrofti mf in three-line thick smears prepared with a measured 60 microliter quantity of finger prick blood collected between 8pm-2am. The species of mf will be determined by morphological criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of W. bancrofti filarial antigenemia (7 years)</measure>
    <time_frame>7 years</time_frame>
    <description>Prevalence of this outcome measure is determined by the percentage (%) of individuals with positive tests for the W. bancrofti filarial antigen. Blood will be tested for filarial antigenemia using the Alere Filariasis Test Strip (FTS).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of O. volvulus microfilaria (7 years)</measure>
    <time_frame>7 years</time_frame>
    <description>Prevalence of O. volvulus microfilaria (mf) is a binary outcome measured by the presence/absence of O. volvulus mf taken from skin snips using Holth corneoscleral punches taken from the buttocks.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Community egg load of soil transmitted helminth (STH) eggs (7 years)</measure>
    <time_frame>7 years</time_frame>
    <description>Community egg load is defined as average stool egg count per species. FLOTAC and Kato-Katz (KK) methods will be used to examine a single stool sample from each subject.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">21862</enrollment>
  <condition>Lymphatic Filariasis</condition>
  <condition>Onchocerciasis</condition>
  <condition>Soil Transmitted Helminth (STH) Infections</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Annual Mass Drug Administration</arm_group_label>
    <description>This group will receive annual mass drug administration (Albendazole 400 mg plus Ivermectin) provided by the Liberian Ministry of Health.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Semiannual Mass Drug Administration</arm_group_label>
    <description>This group will receive semi-annual mass drug administration (Albendazole 400 mg plus Ivermectin) provided by the Liberian Ministry of Health.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Annual versus Semiannual Albendazole plus Ivermectin Mass Drug Administration</intervention_name>
    <description>Annual or semiannual Albendazole plus Ivermectin, administered by the Liberian Ministry of Health.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Annual Mass Drug Administration</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Semiannual Mass Drug Administration</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Albenza (Albendazole); Ivermectin, also known as Mectizan or Stromectol.</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Study procedures include collection of finger prick blood that will be tested for&#xD;
      microfilaremia and for serology testing (antigenemia and antibody testing). Investigators&#xD;
      will also collect skin snips (small superficial skin biopsies) to detect Onchocerca&#xD;
      microfilariae, and stool samples to detect parasitic worm eggs indicative of STH infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All assays will be performed in Liberia (filarial serology tests, MF smears, stool&#xD;
      examinations).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study populations are people who live in areas of Liberia that are co-endemic for&#xD;
        lymphatic filariasis and onchocerciasis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Study areas should be endemic for filariasis and onchocerciasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Study population have limited or no prior experience with MDA. Males and Females&#xD;
             greater than 5 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Children less than 5 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Children who weigh less than 15 kg (33 lb)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gary J Weil, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Washington University School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Peter U Fischer, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Washington University School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Fatorma K Bolay, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Liberian Institute of Biomedical Research</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Liberian Institute of Biomedical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlesville</city>
        <state>Margibi</state>
        <country>Liberia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Liberia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.dolf.wustl.edu/</url>
    <description>Death to Onchocerciasis and Lymphatic Filariasis (DOLF) Project</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>February 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 12, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 18, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 23, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 10, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 10, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 11, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Filariasis</keyword>
  <keyword>Onchocerciasis</keyword>
  <keyword>Albendazole</keyword>
  <keyword>Ivermectin</keyword>
  <keyword>STH Soil Transmitted Helminth infections</keyword>
  <keyword>MDA Mass Drug Administration</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Filariasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Elephantiasis, Filarial</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Onchocerciasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Elephantiasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ivermectin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Albendazole</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>May 9, 2019</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/36/NCT01905436/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>September 23, 2019</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/36/NCT01905436/ICF_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

