<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2192">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on September 19, 2022</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01606891</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>U01HD068990</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01606891</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>NET-Works:Community Preschooler Obesity Prevention</brief_title>
  <acronym>NET-Works</acronym>
  <official_title>Linking Primary Care, Communities and Families to Prevent Obesity Among Preschoolers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Minnesota</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Minnesota</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of the Minnesota center is to integrate primary care, home, and community-based&#xD;
      intervention strategies to promote sustained patterns of change in food intake, physical&#xD;
      activity, and body weight among low income, ethnically diverse children. A culturally matched&#xD;
      family connector will create linkages among the settings to support parents in making home&#xD;
      environment and parenting behavior changes conducive to healthy growth and development in&#xD;
      their children.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim 1 To evaluate the effects of a three-year multi-setting parent-targeted&#xD;
      randomized controlled intervention on the primary outcome, child BMI, compared to a standard&#xD;
      primary care-only intervention among 500 low income ethnic minority two to four year old&#xD;
      children who are at or above the 50th percentile of BMI for age and gender.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis 1: Children in the multi-setting parent-targeted intervention will have a lower&#xD;
      BMI at 24 and 36 months, compared with children in the standard primary care only control&#xD;
      group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim 2 To evaluate the effects of a three-year multi-setting parent-targeted&#xD;
      intervention on secondary outcomes, including change in child energy intake and physical&#xD;
      activity energy expenditure, compared to a standard primary care-only intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis 2: Children in the multi-setting parent-targeted intervention will have lower&#xD;
      energy intake and higher energy expenditure over the three-year period, compared with&#xD;
      children in the standard primary care-only control group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim 3 To evaluate the effects of the multi-setting parent-targeted intervention on&#xD;
      hypothesized mediators of change in dietary intake, physical activity, and BMI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis 3: It is hypothesized that changes in parenting behaviors and the home food and&#xD;
      physical activity environment will mediate changes in child energy intake and expenditure,&#xD;
      and body mass index (BMI).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. Trial design overview NET-Works is a two-arm, randomized controlled trial to test the&#xD;
           efficacy of a multi-setting, multi-component intervention approach to preventing obesity&#xD;
           among racially/ethnically diverse preschool age children. The NET-Works intervention&#xD;
           includes four main components: 1) a pediatric primary care brief counseling&#xD;
           intervention; 2) a home-based intervention delivered by NET-Works family connectors to&#xD;
           support parents in making changes in the home environment and parenting practices to&#xD;
           promote healthful eating and activity patterns; 3) community-based parenting classes&#xD;
           designed to parallel the home-based intervention curriculum and provide social support&#xD;
           to participating parents; and 4) linkages to neighborhood and community resources to&#xD;
           support parents in promoting healthful eating and activity patterns for their children.&#xD;
           Five hundred parent/child dyads were randomized to either the NET-Works intervention or&#xD;
           a usual care comparison condition and followed for three years. Participants were&#xD;
           assessed at baseline and annually. The primary hypothesis is that children randomized to&#xD;
           the NET-Works intervention will have lower BMI (body mass index) at two and three years&#xD;
           post-randomization relative to usual care comparison group children. BMI is the primary&#xD;
           outcome across all four Childhood Obesity Prevention and Treatment Research (COPTR)&#xD;
           trials. Recruitment for the trial began in July 2012 and was completed in December 2013,&#xD;
           with the final three year follow-up data collected in December 2016.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Study setting and population The target population for NET-Works was racially/ethnically&#xD;
           diverse preschool children and their parent or primary caregiver. To reach the intended&#xD;
           population, NET-Works partnered with 12 primary care clinics and three managed health&#xD;
           care systems that serve diverse populations with respect to race, ethnicity and income.&#xD;
           Over 18 months, 500 families were recruited, enrolled and randomized to the intervention&#xD;
           or to the usual care comparison group. Administrative databases and centralized&#xD;
           electronic scheduling systems at the partner clinics provided data needed to target&#xD;
           recruitment efforts on two-to-four year old children residing in certain zip code areas.&#xD;
           The clinics had data from preventive care visits available for calculation of child body&#xD;
           mass index (BMI) percentile to focus recruitment efforts on children who were&#xD;
           potentially BMI-eligible for the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Recruitment Administrative databases and centralized electronic scheduling systems at&#xD;
           three partner health care organizations provided data needed to target families of&#xD;
           two-four year old children whose BMI percentile was at or above the 50th percentile for&#xD;
           age and gender. Clinic liaisons obtained approval from each child's pediatrician to send&#xD;
           a study invitation letter to the parent or primary caregiver. A list of&#xD;
           physician-approved potentially eligible children was shared with the NET-Works&#xD;
           recruitment team. NET-Works sent the parent or primary caregiver a study invitation&#xD;
           letter from the pediatrician and researchers. Approximately five working days later,&#xD;
           NET-Works recruitment staff followed up by phone to provide more information, ask&#xD;
           additional screening questions, and assesses parent/primary caregiver's interest in the&#xD;
           study. If the parent/primary caregiver was interested and the child appeared to be&#xD;
           eligible, a home visit for eligibility confirmation, consent, and data collection was&#xD;
           scheduled. The purpose of this initial home visit was to: 1) explain and discuss the&#xD;
           study, and begin to develop rapport with parents; 2) measure the index child's height&#xD;
           and weight to confirm eligibility; 3) obtain informed consent; and 4) begin the process&#xD;
           of collecting baseline data. Based on our pilot study experience, we anticipated the&#xD;
           majority of the participating parent/caregivers would be female and a significant number&#xD;
           of Hispanic families as well as non-Hispanic White, African American, and multi-race&#xD;
           participants would be recruited.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Randomization Prior to the start of recruitment and enrollment, the study statistician&#xD;
           created 6 blocked randomization schedules, one for each age group (2, 3, 4) by gender&#xD;
           (M, F) stratum, that would equally allocated children to the NET-Works intervention or&#xD;
           the usual care comparison group in blocks of 10 to ensure equivalent study group size.&#xD;
           Parent-child dyads were randomized to treatment and control conditions after completion&#xD;
           of all baseline measures, including data eligibility requirements established by the&#xD;
           COPTR consortium. Data eligibility requirements included valid height and weight&#xD;
           measurement, a minimum of one weekday and one weekend day NDS-R (nutritional data&#xD;
           survey-revised) previous day dietary recall and four days of valid accelerometry data.&#xD;
           The study coordinator randomly assigned the participant to the condition shown in the&#xD;
           next available slot in the stratum-appropriate pre-defined randomization schedule. The&#xD;
           investigators and all assessment staff remained blinded to experimental assignment until&#xD;
           after the final follow-up assessments were completed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. NET-Works intervention The NET-Works intervention was designed to reach into the home&#xD;
           and family environment to influence parent behaviors and attitudes to support changes in&#xD;
           the home that affect food availability, family meals, television viewing, and active&#xD;
           play. Each intervention component would be situated in community settings where parents&#xD;
           and children already live their lives. The intervention was expected to be effective in&#xD;
           part through taking advantage of the settings that families already inhabit, and through&#xD;
           coordination across settings to reinforce and link the messages, resources and feedback&#xD;
           families receive about healthful food choices, physical activity, and body weight for&#xD;
           their child. We believed the neighborhood-based model would be more likely to enhance&#xD;
           class participation, reduce transportation needs/costs, allow the local community&#xD;
           resources to be accessed more easily, and foster outside-of-class interpersonal&#xD;
           connections among parents for enhanced social support.&#xD;
&#xD;
           5.1. Intervention components implementation overview The intervention curricula across&#xD;
           each component (home visiting, parenting classes, neighborhood environment, pediatric&#xD;
           primary care) was developed and refined during the pilot phase of the COPTR consortium.&#xD;
           The intervention was designed to be implemented by trained research staff including a&#xD;
           family connector who would conduct the home visiting and connector check-in calls and&#xD;
           attend the parenting classes, and a parent educator who would conduct the community&#xD;
           parenting classes that were based on the early childhood parenting class model and was&#xD;
           developed in partnership with ECFE (early childhood and family education) in Minneapolis&#xD;
           and St. Paul. The home visiting and parenting classes shared a common set of underlying&#xD;
           curricula that included skills building around general parenting behaviors and the&#xD;
           specific content behaviors targeted by the intervention (e.g., healthful snacks, family&#xD;
           meals, physical activity). The family connector met parents and children in their own&#xD;
           home, tailoring the intervention messages and strategies to best fit with the resources&#xD;
           and motivations of parents. The family connector provided a one-on-one approach to&#xD;
           synergize with the skills and strategies implemented in a group format in the NET-Works&#xD;
           community parenting classes. Both home visiting and parenting classes directly connected&#xD;
           parents to food and physical activity resources that already exist in their neighborhood&#xD;
           (&quot;community links&quot;). Primary care providers bolstered these messages with parents during&#xD;
           annual well-child visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
           5.2. Home visiting The goal of the home visiting was to help parents develop parenting&#xD;
           skills, set goals related to child healthful eating, active play and reduced television&#xD;
           viewing, and provided support for sustaining and building on these behavior and home&#xD;
           environment changes. The dose for the home visiting intervention component was one visit&#xD;
           per month for each of the three years. The family connector built a collaborative,&#xD;
           partnership-based goal setting process for parents to facilitate child behavior change.&#xD;
           Facilitation of the home visits was modeled on Motivational Interviewing, an approach&#xD;
           designed to help individuals explore and resolve ambivalence about behavior change in a&#xD;
           non-confrontational manner. Home visiting included a goal setting process guided by the&#xD;
           family connector, healthful action activities to create norms and skills related to the&#xD;
           targeted behaviors, and resources for links in the community to support healthful&#xD;
           behaviors. Family connectors also checked in with participants to review progress on&#xD;
           goals and provide support in between home visits. Family connector check-in contacts&#xD;
           could be conducted over the telephone or via email. Family connectors had weekly&#xD;
           supervision sessions with a licensed mental health provider with expertise in&#xD;
           Motivational Interviewing to review progress with each participant, problem solve&#xD;
           regarding any challenges that arise, and ensure adherence to the intervention protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
           5.3. Parenting classes The parenting classes were designed to work synergistically with&#xD;
           the home visiting curriculum. The parenting class and the home visiting curriculum both&#xD;
           included topics that addressed parenting skills development, the home food environment,&#xD;
           healthful eating, family meals, television viewing limits, active play, and goal&#xD;
           setting. The parenting class provided a group format where parents could share their&#xD;
           experiences, gain support from other parents and learn from each other. The curriculum&#xD;
           was research-based and facilitated by a trained parent educator. The dose for the&#xD;
           parenting class component was 12 classes per year for each of the three years. The&#xD;
           curriculum in years 2 and 3 built upon and deepen the topics introduced in year 1, and&#xD;
           addressed parenting and developmental issues as children progress from ages 2-7 years of&#xD;
           age. Parent educators also participated in weekly supervision sessions to ensure&#xD;
           adherence to the intervention protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
           5.4. Neighborhood and community initiative The purpose of the neighborhood and community&#xD;
           intervention component was to increase access to, and use of, healthful food, physical&#xD;
           activity, and school readiness resources available in the neighborhood communities where&#xD;
           study participants live. Parents were directly linked with resources in their&#xD;
           neighborhood through both the parenting classes and the family connector home visits.&#xD;
           Community initiatives implemented with the family connector included conducting a&#xD;
           walkability assessment of the family's neighborhood. The family connector reviewed&#xD;
           neighborhood food and physical activity resources with the parent at each home visit,&#xD;
           and encouraged them to use these resources to support their home and behavior changes.&#xD;
           The community links included one school readiness community activity (e.g., a library&#xD;
           visit) to promote developmental parenting, sustain parent interest, and provide active&#xD;
           support for whole child development. Four community links were included in the parenting&#xD;
           class and home visiting curriculum each year of the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
           5.5. Primary care The primary care provider is an influential connection for parents. In&#xD;
           NET-Works, the primary care provider delivered key messages around parent behaviors for&#xD;
           shaping, reinforcing and sustaining healthful child eating and physical activity&#xD;
           behaviors and body weight. To support providers in delivering key messages to parents&#xD;
           during well child visits, a brochure was developed in partnership with the participating&#xD;
           clinic systems. The brochure was used by the primary care provider to converse about&#xD;
           child BMI percentile and strategies parents could use to promote their child's healthful&#xD;
           eating and activity patterns. The NET-Works family connector will also provided&#xD;
           information about progress on intervention goals to the primary care provider on an&#xD;
           annual basis to reinforce continuity and integration of intervention messages. The&#xD;
           primary care intervention linked with the community parenting classes and home visiting&#xD;
           to deliver consistent intervention messages over a sustained time period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Intervention component integration Linkages across the intervention components were&#xD;
           created in several ways with the family connector playing a key role in this&#xD;
           connectivity. Specifically, in addition to conducting home visits, family connectors&#xD;
           facilitated participant entry into parenting classes and also attended parenting&#xD;
           classes. Attending parenting classes allowed the family connector to be knowledgeable&#xD;
           about the parenting class content and the experience their assigned participants were&#xD;
           having during class. This information informed the goal setting that family connectors&#xD;
           and parents worked on during home visits. Family connectors also served as the liaison&#xD;
           between parents and primary care providers. The home visits and parenting classes also&#xD;
           incorporated connections to community resources for physical activity and healthy eating&#xD;
           as described above.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Usual care comparison group The usual care comparison group received the primary care&#xD;
           provider component described above, and quarterly newsletters with information about&#xD;
           their child's general health and wellness and school readiness.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Participant timeline, assessments, and measures Data collection took place in the home&#xD;
           setting at baseline, 12, 24, and 36 months by trained and certified, bilingual English&#xD;
           and Spanish research specialists, blinded to experimental assignment. At 6, 18, and 30&#xD;
           months, a brief telephone survey was conducted. Participants receive a total of $50 in&#xD;
           gift cards for each set of measurement visits (baseline and each subsequent annual&#xD;
           assessment) and a $5 gift card for each brief telephone survey. Data collectors were&#xD;
           trained by the investigators and, for COPTR consortium common measures, by the Research&#xD;
           Coordinating Unit (RCU) according to standardized protocols. COPTR used a&#xD;
           train-the-trainer model. &quot;Master Trainers&quot; who participated in a central training&#xD;
           organized by the RCU were responsible for training and certifying the data collection&#xD;
           staff at their field center. Data collectors were required to demonstrate high inter-&#xD;
           and intra-rater reliability prior to data collection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Statistical analyses The primary efficacy analysis was designed to test whether two to&#xD;
           four year old children who were randomized to the NET-Works program have statistically&#xD;
           and clinically lower BMI at 24 and 36 months post randomization relative to usual care&#xD;
           comparison group children with age at randomization (2, 3, 4), sex (F, M) and BMI at&#xD;
           baseline used as covariates. According to the study protocol, all covariates in the&#xD;
           primary analysis would be measured at baseline prior to randomization and therefore&#xD;
           available for observed and unobserved BMI values.&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Data monitoring and participant safety The data safety and monitoring plan included&#xD;
           assessing adverse events systematically at each data collection visit with direct&#xD;
           queries for all injuries, illnesses or other medical problems requiring a visit to a&#xD;
           medical care provider and related to participation in the study. Serious Adverse Events&#xD;
           (SAEs) were specifically monitored. Adverse events were also be recorded and evaluated&#xD;
           when they came to the attention of study staff between the data collection visits. An&#xD;
           independent Data and Safety Monitoring Board was selected to review study protocols and&#xD;
           provide oversight of recruitment and study progress, data quality and completeness, and&#xD;
           participant safety.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 21, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 21, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>body mass index</measure>
    <time_frame>three years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>energy intake</measure>
    <time_frame>three years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">534</enrollment>
  <condition>Childhood Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>parent-targeted intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>experimental</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Primary Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard primary care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>multi-component/setting parent-targeted intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>parents assigned to this group will be asked to participate in a program of home visiting, community parenting classes, and community food and physical activity resource links</description>
    <arm_group_label>parent-targeted intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A child and his or her parent(s) will be eligible for the study if:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  the two to four year old child is scheduled to receive or eligible for (based on&#xD;
                  an upcoming birthday) a recommended well child visit conducted by a pediatric or&#xD;
                  family practice care provider;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  the child has no medical problems that would preclude study participation as&#xD;
                  determined by the physician conducting the well child visit (e.g. serious disease&#xD;
                  that would make following guidelines for parent encouragement of healthy diet and&#xD;
                  physical activity infeasible);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  the child's BMI is greater than or equal to the 50th percentile according to CDC&#xD;
                  age and sex reference standards&#xD;
                  http://www.cdc.gov/nchs/data/nhanes/growthcharts/bmiage.txt;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  the child's parent/guardian agrees to participation in the study and is not&#xD;
                  planning to move out of the state in the next three years&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  the primary caregiver is willing and able to complete the evaluation measures and&#xD;
                  participate in intervention activities if assigned to the active intervention&#xD;
                  group.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  the parent speaks either English or Spanish.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A child will be excluded if she or he does not meet the above eligibility criteria&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>4 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Simone A French, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Minnesota</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nancy E Sherwood, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Minnesota</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Minnesota Division of Epidemiology &amp; Community Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Minneapolis</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55454</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 23, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 25, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 28, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 10, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 10, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 15, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>preschooler obesity prevention</keyword>
  <keyword>community home visiting parents</keyword>
  <keyword>preschooler excess BMI gain</keyword>
  <keyword>multi-setting/component intervention</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>May 14, 2016</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/91/NCT01606891/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

