<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2238">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on September 19, 2022</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01053078</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0903M60907</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R01DK062440</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>7-09-DCS-02</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01053078</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Naltrexone and Hypoglycemia in Type 1 Diabetes</brief_title>
  <acronym>Naltrexone</acronym>
  <official_title>Study of the Effect of Naltrexone on Cerebral Blood Flow and Hypoglycemia in Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Minnesota</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>American Diabetes Association</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Minnesota</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Low blood sugar is also called hypoglycemia. Usually, it is mild and can be treated quickly&#xD;
      and easily by eating or drinking a small amount of a sugar-rich food. If low blood sugar is&#xD;
      left untreated, it can get worse and cause confusion, clumsiness or fainting. Severe&#xD;
      hypoglycemia can lead to seizures, coma, and even death.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some people with diabetes do not have early warning signs of low blood sugar. This condition&#xD;
      is called hypoglycemia unawareness. It happens when the body stops reacting to low blood&#xD;
      sugar levels and the person does not realize that they need to treat their hypoglycemia. This&#xD;
      can lead to more severe and dangerous hypoglycemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this early study is to see if a drug called naltrexone should be studied more&#xD;
      in people with Type I diabetes and hypoglycemia unawareness. This study will show whether&#xD;
      naltrexone could reduce hypoglycemia unawareness. The study will also show, by using magnetic&#xD;
      resonance imaging (also called MRI), whether naltrexone changes the way blood flows in the&#xD;
      brain when a person is experiencing hypoglycemia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Visit 1&#xD;
&#xD;
      This visit is estimated to last approximately 1 hour.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At this visit, you will be asked to complete a questionnaire about hypoglycemia unawareness.&#xD;
      Some questions about your medical history may be asked in order to make sure you are eligible&#xD;
      to be in this study. You will also have some blood collected for tests that measure how your&#xD;
      liver and kidneys are working. A blood test that measures muscle breakdown will also be done.&#xD;
      If you are a female who could become pregnant, a pregnancy test will also be done. The amount&#xD;
      of blood that will be collected at this visit is approximately three teaspoons. This visit is&#xD;
      estimated to last approximately one hour.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will be asked to wear a continuous glucose monitor (CGMS) around the clock for the seven&#xD;
      days before the MRI study. This involves putting a small plastic sensor under the skin on&#xD;
      your stomach and carrying the monitor that attaches to the sensor. The sensor measures your&#xD;
      glucose and records the readings automatically on the monitor. The monitor is about the size&#xD;
      of the palm of a woman's hand. The information stored on the monitor can be sent to a&#xD;
      computer that the researcher uses. The researcher will insert the CGMS at visit 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Between Visit 1 and Visit 2&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will also be asked to keep careful records for the study every day for the next seven&#xD;
      days. You will be asked to check your blood glucose before each of three meals and before you&#xD;
      go to sleep at night. You will also be asked to write down your blood glucose levels and&#xD;
      bring those records back for the researcher.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 2&#xD;
&#xD;
      Seven days after visit 1 you will be asked to report to the Center for Magnetic Resonance&#xD;
      Research (CMRR) at 7:30AM for your first MRI scan. The study will be done in the morning&#xD;
      after an overnight fast. All subjects will be asked to fast for a minimum of 8 hours before&#xD;
      arriving at the center. The researcher will advise you on how to adjust your insulin regimen&#xD;
      during the 1-2 days before the MRI scan to be sure your blood sugar is in good control when&#xD;
      you arrive at the CMRR.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Alternatively, you may be asked to come to the Clinical Research Unit the night before the&#xD;
      MRI study You will be admitted to the Clinical Research Unit, and stay overnight there. You&#xD;
      will not be given any food after your evening meal until your test is completed at about&#xD;
      lunch time on the following day. Your evening dose of long-acting insulin or your pump will&#xD;
      be held after 6:00 p.m. that evening. Your blood glucose will be measured every 1-2 hours. An&#xD;
      intravenous (IV) catheter will be placed in your arm and will stay there until your test is&#xD;
      over the next day. You will be given insulin and glucose as needed to keep your blood sugars&#xD;
      between 100 and 150 mg/dl through the night leading to testing on the next day. In the&#xD;
      morning, you will be transferred to the Center for Magnetic Resonance Research (CMRR) for an&#xD;
      MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the CMRR, an IV will be placed in each of your arms. This will allow for giving insulin,&#xD;
      glucose and potassium during the test. A third IV will be placed in one of your legs. This&#xD;
      catheter will be put in so that blood can be collected during the test. After the catheter in&#xD;
      your leg is placed you will rest for 30 minutes. After thirty minutes, blood will be&#xD;
      collected from the catheter in your leg for laboratory tests. The test is then ready to&#xD;
      begin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will be given insulin through the catheter in one arm and you will be placed in the MRI&#xD;
      machine. Your glucose will be checked every five minutes throughout the study. Blood will&#xD;
      also be collected every 30 minutes for other laboratory tests. When your glucose drops to 50&#xD;
      mg/dl it will be held at that level for approximately 30 minutes so the measures of blood&#xD;
      flow and glucose concentrations in your brain can be taken. While your blood sugar is&#xD;
      dropping, you will be asked about any symptoms you may feel. After the measures have been&#xD;
      taken, the insulin given through the IV will be stopped and you will be given glucose to&#xD;
      bring it back to a normal level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will be at the CMRR for 4-6 hours. After the test is completed, your IVs will be taken&#xD;
      out, you will resume your usual diabetes treatments, and you will be fed a meal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Between the time you are admitted to the Clinical Research Unit and the time you are&#xD;
      discharged after your MRI test, just less than one cup of blood will be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will be given a supply of naltrexone, the study medication, or placebo, with instructions&#xD;
      for taking the medication over the next four weeks. You will be randomly assigned (like a&#xD;
      flip of a coin) to naltrexone, or to a placebo (a pill that does not contain any medicine).&#xD;
      Neither you nor your study doctor will know which study treatment (placebo or naltrexone) you&#xD;
      are receiving. If it becomes necessary to know for medical reasons, the information will be&#xD;
      made available.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Between Visits 2 and 3&#xD;
&#xD;
      While you are taking naltrexone or placebo you will be asked not to use Tylenol (or any other&#xD;
      product containing acetaminophen), Advil (or any other product containing ibuprofen or a&#xD;
      non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drug), or aspirin. You will also be asked to avoid alcohol&#xD;
      while taking naltrexone. If you have any concerns or questions about using these substances&#xD;
      during the time you are taking naltrexone please ask the study doctor or coordinator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You should always take your naltrexone dose right after you eat a meal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Days 1 - 5: Starting the day after your MRI test, you will be asked to take one 25 mg tablet&#xD;
      of naltrexone or placebo each day for the next five days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Days 6 - 10: On these days you will be asked to take one 50 mg tablet of naltrexone or&#xD;
      placebo each day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Days 11- 14: On these days you will be asked to take one 50 mg tablet of naltrexone or&#xD;
      placebo twice each day. Visit 2 for the study will occur on Day 14.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 3&#xD;
&#xD;
      This visit is estimated to last approximately 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will come to the Clinical Research Unit for a short visit on this day. Blood will be&#xD;
      collected for tests that measure how your liver and kidneys are working. A blood test that&#xD;
      measures muscle breakdown will also be done. Just like at visit 1, the amount of blood&#xD;
      collected from you at this visit will be approximately three teaspoons.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study doctor or coordinator will also talk to you about how you are feeling. You will be&#xD;
      asked about whether you have been taking naltrexone or placebo according to the study plan.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Between Visits 3 and 4&#xD;
&#xD;
      Days 15 - 21: On these days you will be asked to take one 50 mg tablet of naltrexone or&#xD;
      placebo twice each day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 4&#xD;
&#xD;
      This visit is estimated to last approximately 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will be asked to wear a continuous glucose monitor (CGMS) around the clock for the seven&#xD;
      days before the MRI study. This involves putting a small plastic sensor under the skin on&#xD;
      your stomach and carrying the monitor that attaches to the sensor. The sensor measures your&#xD;
      glucose and records the readings automatically on the monitor. The monitor is about the size&#xD;
      of the palm of a woman's hand. The information stored on the monitor can be sent to a&#xD;
      computer that the researcher uses. The researcher will insert the CGMS at visit 4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Between Visits 4 and 5&#xD;
&#xD;
      Days 22 - 28: On these days you will be asked to take one 50 mg tablet of naltrexone or&#xD;
      placebo twice each day. You will take your last study dose of naltrexone or placebo on Day&#xD;
      28.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Starting on Day 22, just like in the first part of this study, you will also be asked to keep&#xD;
      careful records for the study every day during this time. You will be asked to check your&#xD;
      blood glucose before each of three meals and before you go to sleep at night. You will also&#xD;
      be asked to write down your blood glucose levels and bring those records back for the&#xD;
      researcher.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 5&#xD;
&#xD;
      Just like in the first part of the study, you will be asked to report to the Center for&#xD;
      Magnetic Resonance Research (CMRR) at 7:30AM for your first MRI scan. The study will be done&#xD;
      in the morning after an overnight fast. All subjects will be asked to fast for a minimum of 8&#xD;
      hours before arriving at the center. The researcher will advise you on how to adjust your&#xD;
      insulin regimen during the 1-2 days before the MRI scan to be sure your blood sugar is in&#xD;
      good control when you arrive at the CMRR.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Alternatively, you will be asked to come to the Clinical Research Unit the night before the&#xD;
      MRI study. You will come in the day before you take your last dose of naltrexone or placebo.&#xD;
      You will be admitted to the Clinical Research Unit, and stay overnight there. You will not be&#xD;
      given any food after your evening meal until your test is completed at about lunch time on&#xD;
      the following day. Your evening dose of long-acting insulin or your pump will be held after&#xD;
      6:00 p.m. that evening. Your blood glucose will be measured every 1-2 hours. An intravenous&#xD;
      (IV) catheter will be placed in your arm and will stay there until your test is over the next&#xD;
      day. You will be given insulin and glucose as needed to keep your blood sugars between 100&#xD;
      and 150 mg/dl through the night leading to testing on the next day. In the morning, you will&#xD;
      be transferred to the Center for Magnetic Resonance Research (CMRR) for an MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood will be collected for tests that measure how your liver and kidneys are working. A&#xD;
      blood test that measures muscle breakdown will also be done.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The procedures for Visit 5 will be exactly the same as the procedures in Visit 2. The only&#xD;
      difference is that you will not be given any naltrexone or placebo at the end of the visit.&#xD;
      When you complete Visit 5, your participation in the study has been completed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the CMRR, an IV will be placed in each of your arms. This will allow for giving insulin,&#xD;
      glucose and potassium during the test. A third IV will be placed in one of your legs. This&#xD;
      catheter will be put in so that blood can be collected during the test. After the catheter in&#xD;
      your leg is placed you will rest for 30 minutes. After thirty minutes, blood will be&#xD;
      collected from the catheter in your leg for laboratory tests. The test is then ready to&#xD;
      begin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will be given insulin through the catheter in one arm and you will be placed in the MRI&#xD;
      machine. Your glucose will be checked every five minutes throughout the study. Blood will&#xD;
      also be collected every 30 minutes for other laboratory tests. When your glucose drops to 50&#xD;
      mg/dl it will be held at that level for approximately 30 minutes so the measures of blood&#xD;
      flow and glucose concentrations in your brain can be taken. While your blood sugar is&#xD;
      dropping, you will be asked about any symptoms you may feel. After the measures have been&#xD;
      taken, the insulin given through the IV will be stopped and you will be given glucose to&#xD;
      bring it back to a normal level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will be at the CMRR for 4-6 hours. After the test is completed, your IVs will be taken&#xD;
      out, you will resume your usual diabetes treatments, and you will be fed a meal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Between the time you are admitted to the Clinical Research Unit and the time you are&#xD;
      discharged after your MRI test, just less than one cup of blood will be collected.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cerebral Blood Flow</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hypoglycemia Symptom Score</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Hypoglycemia symptom score is determined by a standardized 12-item questionnaire. Participants rank hypoglycemic symptoms on a Likert scale from 0 (no symptoms) to 6 (severe symptoms). Total score is a sum of the 12 items scores with a total score range from 0 to 72. Higher scores indicated increased severity of symptoms associated with hypoglycemia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">29</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 1 Diabetes</condition>
  <condition>Hypoglycemia Unawareness</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Naltrexone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Naltrexone</intervention_name>
    <description>1 month treatment; Naltrexone 25mg once daily for 5 days, then 50 mg once daily for 23 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Naltrexone</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ReVia</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>1 month treatment; placebo tablet once daily for 28 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18-65 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Type 1 diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypoglycemia unawareness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capable of providing informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant regular use of acetaminophen, aspirin or ibuprofen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of drug or alcohol abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Elevations in ALT (Alanine Aminotransferase), AST (Aspartate Aminotransferase),&#xD;
             creatinine or history of hepatitis, liver failure, or renal failure/insufficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Elizabeth R Seaquist, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Minnesota</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Minnesota</name>
      <address>
        <city>Minneapolis</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55455</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 19, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 20, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 21, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>September 4, 2014</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>September 4, 2014</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Estimate">September 12, 2014</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 27, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 27, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Type 1 diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Hypoglycemia unawareness</keyword>
  <keyword>low blood sugar</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Unconsciousness</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypoglycemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Naltrexone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>August 17, 2012</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/78/NCT01053078/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Naltrexone</title>
          <description>1 month treatment; Naltrexone 25mg once daily for 5 days, then 50 mg once daily for 23 days</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P2">
          <title>Placebo</title>
          <description>1 month treatment; placebo tablet once daily for 28 days</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Overall Study</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="14"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="15"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="10"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="12"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="4"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="3"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Naltrexone</title>
          <description>1 month treatment; Naltrexone 25mg once daily for 5 days, then 50 mg once daily for 23 days</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B2">
          <title>Placebo</title>
          <description>1 month treatment; placebo tablet once daily for 28 days</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B3">
          <title>Total</title>
          <description>Total of all reporting groups</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="10"/>
            <count group_id="B2" value="12"/>
            <count group_id="B3" value="22"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>&lt;=18 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Between 18 and 65 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="10"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="12"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="22"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>&gt;=65 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>years</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="47" spread="13"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="39" spread="10"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="42" spread="14"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="12"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="10"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Region of Enrollment</title>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>United States</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="10"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="12"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="22"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Cerebral Blood Flow</title>
        <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Naltrexone</title>
            <description>Double blind placebo comparable&#xD;
Naltrexone: 1 month treatment&#xD;
Naltrexone: Naltrexone 25 mg once daily with dose escalation to 50 mg BID to day 28</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Placebo</title>
            <description>Naltrexone: 1 month treatment&#xD;
Naltrexone: Naltrexone 25 mg once daily with dose escalation to 50 mg BID to day 28</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Cerebral Blood Flow</title>
          <units>percentage of signal intensity change</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="10"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="12"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="1.7" spread="1.9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="1.3" spread="3.3"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Hypoglycemia Symptom Score</title>
        <description>Hypoglycemia symptom score is determined by a standardized 12-item questionnaire. Participants rank hypoglycemic symptoms on a Likert scale from 0 (no symptoms) to 6 (severe symptoms). Total score is a sum of the 12 items scores with a total score range from 0 to 72. Higher scores indicated increased severity of symptoms associated with hypoglycemia.</description>
        <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Naltrexone</title>
            <description>1 month treatment; Naltrexone 25mg once daily for 5 days, then 50 mg once daily for 23 days</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Placebo</title>
            <description>1 month treatment; placebo tablet once daily for 28 days</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Hypoglycemia Symptom Score</title>
          <description>Hypoglycemia symptom score is determined by a standardized 12-item questionnaire. Participants rank hypoglycemic symptoms on a Likert scale from 0 (no symptoms) to 6 (severe symptoms). Total score is a sum of the 12 items scores with a total score range from 0 to 72. Higher scores indicated increased severity of symptoms associated with hypoglycemia.</description>
          <units>score on a scale</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="10"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="12"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="12.6" spread="7.5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="14.5" spread="12.2"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Naltrexone</title>
          <description>1 month treatment; Naltrexone 25mg once daily for 5 days, then 50 mg once daily for 23 days</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E2">
          <title>Placebo</title>
          <description>1 month treatment; placebo tablet once daily for 28 days</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, all-cause mortality</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="10"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="12"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="10"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="12"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>0</frequency_threshold>
        <default_assessment>Non-systematic Assessment</default_assessment>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="3" subjects_at_risk="10"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="12"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Gastrointestinal disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>diarrhea</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="3" subjects_at_risk="10"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="12"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Nervous system disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>headache</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="3" subjects_at_risk="10"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="12"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>Principal Investigators are NOT employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>There is NOT an agreement between Principal Investigators and the Sponsor (or its agents) that restricts the PI's rights to discuss or publish trial results after the trial is completed. </restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Elizabeth Seaquist</name_or_title>
      <organization>University of Minnesota</organization>
      <phone>612 624 9176</phone>
      <email>seaqu001@umn.edu</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

